Halpern family fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- George and Ida Halpern records, 1900 - 1989; F-58-3; 13 cm of textual records 88 photographs 68 transparencies
  - Incoming Letters, 1960 - 1969; F-58-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Incoming Letters, 1970 - 1979; F-58-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Incoming Letters, 1980 - 1987; F-58-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Incoming Letters, [19--]; F-58-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Legal Documents, 1955; F-58-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Philanthropic activities - Halpern Centre, SFU, 1984 - 1989; F-58-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Philanthropic activities - miscellaneous donations, 1985 - 1989; F-58-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
  - Philanthropic activities - Works of Art, SFU, 1983 - 1984; F-58-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 58-16)
- Fanny Halpern records, 1908 - 1953; F-58-4; 50 cm of textual records 52 photographs; Language: some of the material is in German.
  Series includes records relating to and created by Fanny Gisela Halpern.
  - Personal papers, 1908 - 1953; F-58-4-1; 16 cm of textual records 31 photographs
    Subseries consists of biographical information, personal papers, legal documents, autograph books and notebooks. Also includes letters written to Fanny by her parents, and letters written by Fanny to secure repayment of her loan of $19,000 to the Augustinian Fathers of Shanghai.
    - Biographical Information, 1940 - 1952; F-58-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 58-17, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Personal Papers (1/2), 1925 - 1951; F-58-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-17, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Personal Papers (2/2), 1925 - 1951; F-58-4-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-17, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Autograph books and notebook, 1908 - 1922; F-58-4-1-0-4
      - Notebook, [19--]; F-58-4-1-0-4-1 (Bound volume OBJ-3114)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item42.
      - Autograph book, 1908 - 1911; F-58-4-1-0-4-2 (Bound volume OBJ-3115)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-4-1-0-4.
      - Autograph book, 1915 - 1922; F-58-4-1-0-4-3 (Bound volume OBJ-3116)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item43.
    - Incoming Letters From Her Parents, 1933 - 1939; F-58-4-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 58-17, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence Re Loan Repayment, 1949 - 1950; F-58-4-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 58-17)
    - Legal Documents, 1952 - 1953; F-58-4-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 58-18)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1940 - 1951; F-58-4-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
  - Medical activities records, 1920 - 1952; F-58-4-2; 22 cm of textual records 21 photographs
    Subseries consists of personal and professional correspondence, patient notes, notebook of clinical data, scrapbook of newspaper clippings about Fanny's career, reprints of published articles, speeches on medical topics given by Fanny at various conferences and meetings, and lecture notes for some of her courses in neurology and psychiatry.
    - Correspondence - Incoming Letters, 1920 - 1929; F-58-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence - Incoming Letters (1/2), 1930 - 1939; F-58-4-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence - Incoming Letters (2/2), 1930 - 1939; F-58-4-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence (1/2), 1940 - 1949; F-58-4-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence (2/2), 1940 - 1949; F-58-4-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Correspondence, 1950 - 1952; F-58-4-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Miscellaneous Medical Papers, 1925 - 1951; F-58-4-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 58-18, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1932 - 1938; F-58-4-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 58-19, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
      - Newspaper clippings scrap book, 1932 - 1936; F-58-4-2-0-8-1 (Bound volume OBJ-3117)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item41.
    - Reprints, 1922 - 1938; F-58-4-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 58-19, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Speeches, 1935 - 1949; F-58-4-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 58-19, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Teaching Notes, 1934; F-58-4-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 58-19, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
  - Reference files, 1935 - 1952; F-58-4-3; 13 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of various files relating to organizations, such as the Chinese Medical Association; subjects of interest, such as aphasia; or publications, such as the Shanghai Medical Journal.
    - Aphasia Among the Chinese, 1948; F-58-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 58-20, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Chinese Medical Association, 1935 - 1938; F-58-4-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-20)
    - Mental Hygiene in China, 1950 - 1952; F-58-4-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-20, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Psychiatry in China, 1936 - 1950; F-58-4-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 58-20, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - Shanghai Medical News, 1935 - 1948; F-58-4-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 58-20, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3277)
    - St. John's University Catalogues, 1936 - 1938; F-58-4-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 58-20)
- Simon and Rosalie Halpern records, 1865 - 1951; F-58-5; 5 cm of textual records 40 photographs
  Series consists of the personal papers of Simon and Rosalie Halpern including birth certificate, identity card, professional certification, passport, immigration papers, and other material. Also includes personal letters from Fanny, George and Ida, and friends.
  - Rosalie Halpern--Personal Papers, 1918 - 1951; F-58-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
  - Rosalie Halpern--Incoming Letters, 1915 - 1948; F-58-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
  - Simon Halpern--Personal Papers, 1865 - 1939; F-58-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
- Memorabilia and audio-visual material, 1871 - 1986; F-58-6; 42 cm of textual records and other material; Physical description: series includes ca. 375 photographs, 98 colour transparencies, 9 contact sheets, 40 artifacts, 4 audio discs, and 4 audio cassettes.
  Series consists of memorabilia (artifacts), photographic prints, transparencies and contact sheets relating to George, Ida, Fanny, Simon and Rosalie Halpern. Also includes four phonograph recordings primarily related to Ida Halpern's research into Pacific Northewest Indian music.
  - Memorabilia and artifacts, 1871 - 1978; F-58-6-1; 8 cm of textual records 40 artifacts
    Subseries contains memorabilia such as Chinese money, coin collection, and George Halpern's advertising materials. Includes artifacts, certificates, and display materials.
    - Masonic ceremony book (cover inscribed), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-1 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item1.
    - Masonic ceremony book, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-2 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item2.
    - Yom Kipper program book, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-3 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item3.
    - The Book of Constitutions, 1968; F-58-6-1-0-0-4 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item4.
    - Free Masonry and the Bible, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-5 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item5.
    - Jewish prayer book (in Hebrew), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-6 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item6.
    - Medical equipment in metal case (6 pieces), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-7 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Artefacts
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item7.
    - Medical equipment - stethoscope, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-8 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item8.
    - Medical equipment - knee hammer, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-9 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item9.
    - Dr. Halpern's Vitamin Pills - box with two samples, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-10 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item10.
    - Dr. Halpern's Vitamin Pills - glass jar, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-11 (Artifact box - small 58-25)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item11.
    - Dr. F. G. Halpern nameplate (with Chinese writing), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-12 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item12.
    - Dr. George Halpern nameplate, President Brock House Society, 1978; F-58-6-1-0-0-13 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item13.
    - Dr. S. Halpern nameplate, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-14 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item14.
    - Eyeglasses in metal case, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-15 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item15.
    - Eyeglasses in oval case, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-16 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item16.
    - Chinese box with 3 metal bowls inside, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-17 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item17.
    - Stamp - "Dr. Halpern's Vitamin Chocolates", [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-18 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item18.
    - Stamp - "Children Chew Them Like Candy", [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-19 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item19.
    - Stamp - "Dr. Fanny Halpern", [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-20 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item20.
    - Leaf-shaped hairclip (black), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-21 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item21.
    - Dr. Halpern's Vitamin Chocolate Tablets container (labels inside), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-22 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item22.
    - Silver square metal vitamin container, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-23 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item23.
    - Krupp-Stahl V2A metal vitamin container, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-24 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item24.
    - "Stamin" cardboard medicine box (empty), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-25 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item25.
    - "Dr. Halpern's Vitamin Chocolate Tablets" labels (bound), [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-26 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item26.
    - Fanny Halpern nameplate, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-27 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item27.
    - Shanghai General Hospital nameplate in Chinese [Fanny], [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-28 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item28.
    - Universitas Viennae bronze medal in blue felt case, 1965; F-58-6-1-0-0-29 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item29.
    - Red Cross medal 1864-1914 (large), F-58-6-1-0-0-30 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item30.
    - Red Cross medal 1864-1914 (small), F-58-6-1-0-0-31 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item31.
    - Handkerchief and lace, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-32 (Artifact box - small 58-26)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item32.
    - Etched glass picture frame with faded print, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-33 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Photographic materials
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item33.
    - George Halpern's masonic apron, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-34 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item34.
    - Jewish prayer shawl, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-35 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item35.
    - Black yarmulke, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-36 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item36.
    - Turquiose yarmulke, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-37 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item37.
    - Torah scrolls, [19--?]; F-58-6-1-0-0-38 (Artifact box - small 58-27)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item38.
    - Memorabilia such as Chinese money, coin collection, advertising materials, [19--]; F-58-6-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
    - Display materials: (copies of articles and photographs, etc.) 1/3, [19--]; F-58-6-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
    - Display materials: (copies of articles and photographs, etc.) 2/3, [19--]; F-58-6-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
    - Display materials: (copies of articles and photographs, etc.) 3/3, [19--]; F-58-6-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
    - Certificates, [18--] - 1973; F-58-6-1-0-5
    - Music Books, [19--]; F-58-6-1-0-6
    - Composers' autographs (G. Mahler, R. Strauss, G. Puccini, C. Schumann), 1871 - 1907; F-58-6-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 58-21)
      Restricted in whole
  - Photographic material, 1900 - 1985; F-58-6-2; 25 cm of textual records ca. 375 photographs 98 colour transparencies 9 contact sheets
    Subseries consists of approximately 375 black and white or colour prints, 98 colour transparencies, and 9 contact sheets. The prints appear to be mainly silver gelatin prints, although some of the older portraits are probably albumin prints. The photographs and transparencies date from ca. 1900 to 1989.
    The archivist found the material scattered throughout several boxes. She grouped the prints according to the Halpern family member who was the principal subject, and she numbered the prints consecutively with an "H" designation before each number. Within the broad groupings by person, there is some further subdivision by type of photograph (i.e., portrait), or by activity (e.g., scientific activities, leisure activities).
    Photographic materials; Graphic materials
    - George Halpern--Portraits, H1-H29, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-1 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - George Halpern--Community Activities, H30-H38, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-2 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - George Halpern--Leisure Activities, H39-H48, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-3 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - George Halpern--Scientific Activities, H49-H56, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-4 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - Ida Halpern--Portraits, H57-H67, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-5 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - Ida Halpern--Leisure and Community Activities, Travel, H68-H144, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-6 (Clamshell box 58-30)
    - George and Ida Halpern--Leisure Activities (1/2), H145-H172, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-7 (Clamshell box 58-30)
    - George and Ida Halpern--Leisure Activities (2/2), H173-H204, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-8 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - George and Ida Halpern--Community Activities, H205-H214, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-9 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - Fanny Halpern--Portraits, Leisure Activities (1/2), H215-H232, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-10 (Clamshell box 58-29)
    - Fanny Halpern--Portraits, Leisure Activities (2/2), H233-H262, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-11 (Clamshell box 58-30)
    - Fanny Halpern--Medical Activities, H263-H281, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-12 (Clamshell box 58-30)
    - Shanghai Mercy Hospital, H281a-H281x, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-13 (Clamshell box 58-30)
    - Rosalie Halpern--Portraits, H282-H296, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-14 (Clamshell box 58-31)
    - Simon Halpern--Portraits, H297-H315, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-15 (Clamshell box 58-31)
    - Simon and Rosalie Halpern--Portraits, H316-H321, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-16 (Clamshell box 58-31)
    - Halpern Family--unknown photographs, H322-H335, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-17 (Clamshell box 58-31)
    - Halpern Centre--SFU, H336-346, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-18 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Transparencies--98:, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-19 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Contact Sheets (9 sheets from undeveloped film found in various boxes). Possibly some photos of the Halperns' original trip to Canada; also, vacation scenes, etc., [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-20 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Contact Sheet Negatives, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-21 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Photographs of Ida and George Halpern from Doug Cole, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-22 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Photographs of Ida Halpern from Janet Menzies, Art Gallery, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-23 (Clamshell box 58-32)
    - Framed Photograph - Fanny Halpern, [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-24
    - George Halpern with Chemical Institute of Canada (O/S photo), [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-25
    - Ida Halpern at piano (O/S photo), [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-26
    - Mass at a church in Shanghai? (O/S photo), [19--]; F-58-6-2-0-27
    - Fanny Halpern and Doctors/staff at the Shanghai Mercy Hospital (O/S photo), 1947; F-58-6-2-0-28
    - Ida Halpern photographs, [ca 1942] - [ca 1985]; F-58-6-2-0-29 (Clamshell box 58-32)
  - Sound recordings, 1949 - 1986; F-58-6-3; 7 sound recordings; Physical description: series comprises 7 sound recordings on 4 phonograph records and 2 audio cassettes.
    Subseries consists of three commercial phonograph recordings (Folkways Records) relating to Ida Halpern's research into the music of the Pacific Northwest Indians. Also includes one phonograph recording, "Music I Like," by Ida Halpern, made from a CBC broadcast, October 16, 1949, and an interview with Ida Halpern (undated).
    - West Coast Indian Music, 8 August 1967; F-58-6-3-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3118)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item39.
    - SFU Ida Halpern interview, [196-?]; F-58-6-3-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3119)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-item40.
    - "Music I Like": CBC broadcast by Ida Halpern, October 16, 1949; F-58-6-3-0-0-1 (Audio disc OBJ-1074, Audio cassette OBJ-1078, Audio cassette OBJ-1079)
      Canadian Broadcasting Corporation; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-6-3-0-1.
    - Indian Music of the Pacific Northwest Coast, 1967; F-58-6-3-0-0-3 (Audio disc OBJ-1075)
      Folkways Records and Service Corp.; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-6-3-0-2.
    - Nootka: Indian Music of the Pacific Northwest Coast, 1974; F-58-6-3-0-0-6 (Audio disc OBJ-1076)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-6-3-0-3.
    - Haida: Indian Music of the Pacific Northwest Coast, 1986; F-58-6-3-0-0-7 (Audio disc OBJ-1077)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-58-6-3-0-4.
    - Excerpt: Between Ourselves, 15 February 1967; F-58-6-3-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3118)